# Jenna Westendorf

# Software Engineer

in linkedin.com/in/jenna-westendorf/ ♀ github.com/jleewest ▶ jenna-westendorf-portfolio.netlify.app/

# **PROFILE**

Full-Stack Developer with 15+ years working collaboratively in diverse team environments to deliver quality results and cultivate supportive and productive team environments in education, social work, nonprofit, and outdoor recreation.

My career has always focused on advancing the capacity for people and organizations to achieve positive impacts. I am a self-driven team builder and outdoor enthusiast with an extensive background in organizational behavior, promoting psychological safety in team development processes, project management, software design and development, and a commitment to continuous learning.

# **SKILLS**

React | Typescript | Javascript | Node.js | Express | Koa | SQL | Postgres | MongoDB

Mongoose | Sequelize | Prisma | Angular | Figma | CSS | Material UI | Bootstrap

APIs | Clerk | GitHub | Responsive Web Design | Vitest | Cypress

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Full-Stack Engineer, California Writers Club

2023 - present

React | Node.js | Express | Postgres | Sequelize | Clerk | Vanilla CSS | Figma

- Worked collaboratively with the California Writers Club president to develop an application designed to connect 2200 writers across California
- Sole responsibility and accountability for building the client and server, designing a user-friendly interface and implementing features to enhance user experience
- Orchestrated project timeline and managed tasks to ensure all features were ready by designated deadline

# **Software Engineer**, Share With Otters

2023 - 2024

React | Typescript | Node.js | Express | Prisma | Postgres | Vitest | Cypress | Material UI

- Led a remote team across different timezones in developing a full-stack application, facilitating team meetings and task management to ensure timely completion and adherence to quality standards before all deadlines
- Formulated idea and design using Figma, aligning design and features with application goals and company mission
- Engineered 90% of client and 100% of server
- Delineated all logic and data modeling required for the app
- Mentored software development team in building assigned components and using new frameworks, resulting in increased team productivity and cohesion

### Software Developer, CashDash

2023 - 2024

Typescript | Cypress | Vitest | Jest | Chart.js

- Improved a legacy codebase by integrating 45 new unit, integration, and end-to-end tests
- Converted code from JavaScript to Typescript, enhancing code quality and maintainability
- Fixed bugs, refactored code, and added new features, leading to enhanced readability a 450% increase in performance

#### Course Director | Lead Instructor, Outward Bound

2015 - 2024

- Implemented course vision and goals, resulting in high-quality educational experiences for participants
- Built productive and supportive team environments, fostering collaboration and growth among staff
- Oversaw course structure and safety
- Facilitated team meetings, including collaborative and solution-focused planning
- Provided feedback and mentorship opportunities for staff, contributing to their professional development
- Maintained high-quality paperwork and communication with program team, ensuring compliance with program standards and promoting transparency throughout the organization.

## School Social Worker, Tucson Unified School District

2022 - 2023

- Assessed and addressed psychological safety and academic support needs for every student on campus, specializing in serving students with emotional disabilities
- Led school leadership team to develop and implement a Positive Behavior Intervention System, resulting in an improvement of school culture, student engagement, and academic success
- Worked with teachers to individualize student academic instruction, maximizing teacher effectiveness
- Promoted social-emotional learning and fostered positive connections through individual and group sessions

# **EDUCATION**

**Software Engineer**, Codeworks

2023 - 2024

Masters in Social Work, San Francisco State University

2016 - 2018

#### BA in Interdisciplinary Studies,

2008 - 2012

University of California, Berkeley Emphasis: Disparities in Education

# **CERTIFICATES**

Frontend Developer • Advanced Responsive Web Development • Advanced React Development

# **AWARDS**

#### Harvest Scene Award, Outward Bound

2023

For outstanding dedication and attention to course quality and for consistent willingness to go above and beyond job expectations

For exceptional service to the community